<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sachin Chaulagai</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Sachin Chaulagai</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 14:33:02 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Beginner friendly Hand-on Project on AWS S3 — Part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/s3-p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 14:33:02 +1100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/s3-p1/</guid>
      <description>I want to help beginner gain some confident on their journey in cloud and tech. I will be posting tutorials and lessons on cloud tech and security such that its more understandable and have not burden but fun and easy to comprehend. Let’s start with a service provided by AWS, called Amazon S3.&#xA;You ever heard about S3? No! Ever used Google Drive to store your files online? Yes! It’s a primary example of how object storage works.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s IaC (Infrastructure as a Code) ???</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/iac/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 10:16:10 +0545</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/iac/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s IaC (Infrastructure as a Code) ??? Introduction Have you ever setup a virtual machine? You might know about using an ISO file to load in Oracle Virtual Box, going through all the steps on by one to install the ISO on the Virtual Hard-Disk and that&amp;rsquo;s a lot of time being wasted. Well, to save some time you might have backed up you VM (of course Virtual Machine) and used OVA to load your VM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Projects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 10:32:54 +0545</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/</guid>
      <description>Learn Docker ANZ Cyber Security Management Completed a simulation focussed on identifying cybersecurity threats at ANZ Investigated e-mails to report suspicious items Analysed a Packet Capture file using an open source tool to identify and investigate any potential threats </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>$whoami</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/whoami/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 09:25:44 +0545</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/whoami/</guid>
      <description>Professional Experience Organization Designation Year DigiTech Nepal Cloud Security Researcher Dec 2022 - Present AwakeTech Solutions DevSecOps Engineer Contract Softwarica College Of IT &amp;amp; E-Commerce Teaching Assistant Aug 2020 - March 2022 TechKraft Inc. Cloud Developer Jan 2021 - Sept 2021 Eminence Ways Cyber Security Intern March 2020 - July 2020 Academic &amp;amp; Certification Coventry University: Bachelor of Science in Ethical Hacking and Cyber Security 2019 - 2022 Coventry ID: 9633953 AWS Certification: AWS Cloud Practitioner Cisco Networking Academy: Cisco ID: CSCO13561807 CCNA Routing &amp;amp; Switching Cisco DevNet Associate CCNA Cyber Operations Certification Verification DevNet Associate https://www.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-dns-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/how-dns-works/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
